Guide to the Claire Kincannon theatre collection, 1955-2011
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 3: Broadway and London Productions, 1955-2007; (3 boxes)
  - La Ronde, Circle in the Square Theatre, NYC, June 22 - November 27, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - A View from the Bridge, Coronet Theatre, NYC, Beginning October 10, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Bus Stop, The Music Box Theatre, NYC, Beginning October 17, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Cat on a Hot Tin Roof, Morosco Theatre, Beginning October 17, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Plain and Fancy, Winter Garden Theatre, NYC, Beginning October 17, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Tiger at the Gates, The Plymouth Theatre, NYC, Beginning October 17, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Will Success Spoil Rock Hunter?, Belasco Theatre, NYC, Beginning October 17, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Witness for the Prosecution, Henry Milley's Theatre, NYC, Beginning October 17, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Fanny, The Majestic Theatre, NYC, Beginning October 24, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Inherit the Wind, National Theatre, NYC, Beginning October 24, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Silk Stockings, The Imperial Theatre, NYC, Beginning October 24, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - The Diary of Anne Frank, The Cort Theatre, NYC, Beginning 24, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - The Desk Set, The Broadhusrt Theatre, NYC, Beginning October 24, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Pipe Dream, Sam S. Shubert Theatre, NYC, Beginning March 12, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - The Apple Cart, The Plymouth Theatre, NYC, Beginning October 29, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Too Late the Phalarope, Belasco Theatre, NYC, Beginning October 29, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Major Barbara, Martin Beck Theatre, NYC, Beginning October 30, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Middle of the Night, ANTA Theatre, NYC, Beginning November 5, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - My Fair Lady, Mark Hellinger Theatre, NYC, Beginning November 5, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Separate Tables, The Music Box Theatre, NYC, Beginning November 5, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - The Matchmaker, The Royale Theatre, NYC, Beginning November 5, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - The Most Happy Fella, The Imperial Theatre, NYC, Beginning November 5, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Long Day's Journey Into Night, Helen Hays Theatre, NYC, Beginning November 12, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - Child of Fortune, Royale Theatre, NYC, Beginning November 13, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - A Very Special Baby, The Playhouse, NYC, Beginning November 14, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - I am a Camera, Actor's Playhouse, NYC, ca. 1956 (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - Look Back in Anger, John Golden Theatre, NYC, Beginning June 9, 1958 (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - Look Homeward, Angel, Ethel Barrymore Theatre, NYC, ca. 1958 (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - Sunrise at Campobello, Cort Theatre, NYC, ca. 1958 (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - The Dark at the Top of the Stairs, The Music Box Theatre, NYC, ca. 1958 (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - Take Me Along, Shubert Theatre, NYC, 1959-1960 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - The Devil's Advocate, Billy Rose Theatre, NYC, May 15, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Becket, Hudson Theatre, NYC, May 22, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Camelot, Majestic Theatre, NYC, May 22, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - The Happiest Girl in the World, Martin Beck Theatre, May 22, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - The Unsinkable Molly Brown, Winter Garden Theatre, NYC, May 22, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Bye Bye Birdie, Sam S. Shubert Theatre, NYC, May 29, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Hedda Gabler, Fourth Street Theatre, NYC, May, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    Playgram.
  - The Balcony, Circle in the Square Theatre, NYC, May, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - The Death of Bessie Smith, and The American Dream, York Playhouse, NYC, May, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Rhinoceros, Longacre Theatre, NYC, ca. 1961 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    Reviews.
  - The Living Theatre Repertory, NYC, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Carnival, Imperial Theatre, NYC, 1961-1962 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Carnival, ANTA Playhouse, NYC, 1961-1963 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - A Delicate Balance, Martin Beck Theatre, NYC, October, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - How's the World Treating You?, The Music Box Theatre, October, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Philadelphia, Here I Come, The Plymouth Theatre, NYC, October, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - The Apple Tree, Shubert Theatre, NYC, October, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Wait Until Dark, George Abbot Theatre, NYC, October, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - America Hurrah, Pocket Theatre, NYC, November 8-15, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    Showcard.
  - The Infantry, 81st Street Theatre, NYC, November 8-15, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Cactus Flower, Royale Theatre, NYC, November, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Fiddler on the Roof, Imperial Theatre, NYC, November, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Mame, Winter Garden Theatre, NYC, November, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Man of La Mancha, ANTA Washington Square Theatre, NYC, November, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - The Rose Tattoo, Billy Rose Theatre, NYC, November, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Cabaret, Broadhurst Theatre, NYC, ca. 1966 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Hail Scrawdyke!, The Booth Theatre, NYC, ca. 1966 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Promenade Magazine, November, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    Magazine.
  - Where Magazine, November, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Masterpieces of Modern Art, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 28)
    Picture book.
  - The Whitney Review, 1965-1966 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    Publication.
  - Starlight Express, Apollo Victoria Theatre, London, ca. March, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Promises, Promises (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - La Cage aux Folles, NY Palace Theatre, January, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Hurlyburly, Ethel Barrymore Theatre, ca. 1984 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - The Seagull, London: Queen's Theatre, August, 1985 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Sweet Bird of Youth, Theatre Royal Haymarket, July 9, 1985 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Daisy Pulls it Off, The Globe Theatre, August, 1985 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Six Degrees of Separation, Vivian Beaumont, February, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Lyndon, John Houseman Theatre, January, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Brand, Theatre Royal Haymarket, August 25, 2003 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - The Coast of Utopia, Vivian Beaumont, March, 2007 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Inherit the Wind, Lyceum Theatre, NYC, March, 2007 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - A Moon for the Misbegotten, Brooks Atkinson Theatre, May, 2007 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Spring Awakening-A New Musical, Eugene O'Neill Theatre, May, 2007 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    Playbill; City Guide.
- Series 4: Film-related Materials, 1943-1992; (1 box)
  The fourth series is film-related materials from 1943-1992, consisting of souvenir books, magazines, and press packets relating to each movie.
  - The Ten Commandments, 1956 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    Souvenir Book.
  - Films and Filming, May, 1958 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    Magazine. Vol 4, no. 8.
  - Films and Filming, June, 1958 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    Magazine. Vol 4, no. 9.
  - The Story of the Making of Ben-Hur, 1959 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    Book.
  - Fiddler on the Roof, 1971 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - The American Film Theatre, 1973-1974 season (Box 29, Folder 6)
    Cinebills for The Iceman Cometh; Luther; Rhinoceros; Lost in the Stars; Butley; The Three Sisters.
  - The American Film Theatre/ The Second Season (Box 29, Folder 7)
    Programs for Jacques Brel is Alive and Well and Living; The Maids; In Celebration; The Man in the Glass Booth; Galileo.
  - Presumed Innocent, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Music in the Movies, The Virginia Festival of American Film, October 24-28, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    Press Packet.
  - Movie Made America, The Virginia Festival of American Film, October 24-27, 1991 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - A Woman's Tale, 1991 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Batman Returns, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    Press Packet; Production Information; Photographs.
  - Filmfest D.C.: The Sixth Annual Washington D.C. International Film Festival, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Grauman's Chinese Theatre souvenir program; 13th gala midsummer drama festival, Pasadena; Hollywood Bowl magazine, circa 1943-1947 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    Program; magazine.
- Series 5: Audiovisual Materials, 1983-1992; (6 boxes)
  The fifth series is audiovisual materials from 1983-1986, consisting of reel-to-reel audiotapes, audiotape cartridges, and videocassettes. Much of the material is from the Behind the Scenes with Claire Kincannon radio program. Behind the Scenes was a three-minute feature on the Performing Arts, and was available via the Public Radio Satellite System.
  - Applause show, undated (Box 34, Reel 1)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at 00:10:08.
  - Behind the Scenes, undated (Box unboxed)
    Videotape.
  - Behind the Scenes, circa 1983-1984 (Box 34)
    Pamphlet.
  - Behind the Scenes: Guitar B-P, undated (Box 34, Reel 2)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Run Time: 00:08:05.
  - Behind the Scenes: H. Hayes/DRM girls, undated (Box 34, Reel 3)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at 00:24:45.
  - Behind the scenes (Kincannon 007), undated (Box 34, Reel 4)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at 00:31:40.
  - Behind the Scenes with Claire Kincannon, undated (Box 39)
    9 discs containing digital access copies and a storage drive with access copies and master digital files.
  - Behind the Scenes with Claire Kincannon, undated (Box 34, Reel 5)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at 00:06:08.
  - Behind the Scenes with Claire Kincannon shows 1 through 3, undated (Box 34, Reel 6)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at 00:16:15.
  - Graduation, Rehau and Caulkins, undated (Box 34, Reel 7)
    5" reel-to-reel audiotape. Run time is 00:07:36.
  - Kincannon 001, undated (Box 34, Cassette 8)
    Audiotape cartridge. Run Time: 00:03:44.
  - Kincannon 002, undated (Box 34, Cassette 9)
    Audiotape cartridge. Run Time: 00:00:44. Tape only contains approximately 2 seconds of audio.
  - Kincannon 014, L. Claire Kincannon Dancing Ink Press, undated (Box 34, Reel 10)
    5" reel-to-reel audiotape. Run Time: 00:03:24.
  - Kincannon 016, L. Claire Kincannon Dancing Ink Press, undated (Box 34, Reel 11)
    5" reel-to-reel audiotape. Approximately 1 minute of silence in the middle of program. Tape entered silence at approximately 00:04:44.
  - Kincannon 026, L. Claire Kincannon Dancing Ink Press, undated (Box 34, Reel 12)
    5" reel-to-reel audiotape. Tape entered silence at approximately 00:07:01.
  - Kincannon 027, L. Claire Kincannon, undated (Box 34, Reel 13)
    10.5" reel-to-reel audiotape rehoused onto 7" reel. Run Time: 00:16:12.
  - Lena; All's well; Return of the Jedi, undated (Box 37, Reel 12)
    10.5" reel-to-reel audiotape. Run Time: 0:23:59.
  - Master show [label half gone], undated (Box 34, Reel 14)
    5" reel-to-reel audiotape. Tape starts mid-program. Program ends at 00:06:04.
  - Master tape weeks 2 and 3, undated (Box 34, Reel 15)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at 00:10:00.
  - Music, undated (Box 37, Reel 1)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Run time is 00:07:28.
  - Tape 2: Frank Daus + Inter, undated (Box 37, Reel 2)
    5" reel-to-reel audiotape. Run Time: 00:11:09.
  - Behind the Scenes: Trouble in Tahiti, July 27 (Box 37, Reel 3)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at 00:04:59.
  - Behind the Scenes: Lena Horne, June 19 (Box 37, Reel 4)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Box reads "1984 October 6". Program ends at 00:03:13.
  - Behind the Scenes #5, September 29, 1983 (Box 37, Reel 5)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at approximately 00:05:46.
  - Behind the Scenes: #5 ORIG Garvin duplicate, September 30, 1983 (Box 37, Reel 6)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at 00:05:46.
  - Behind the Scenes #6, October 6, 1983 (Box 37, Reel 7)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at 00:06:25.
  - Behind the Scenes #8, October 20, 1983 (Box 37, Reel 8)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Run time is 00:04:28.
  - Behind the Scenes, recorded in Denver, CO, "Shadowing", October 21, 1983 (Box 37, Reel 9)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Run time is 00:06:11.
  - Behind the Scenes #10, November 1983? (Box 37, Reel 10)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at 00:05:37.
  - Behind the Scenes #11, November 10, 1983? (Box 37, Reel 11)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at 00:05:02.
  - Behind the Scenes #12: Evita, November 18, 1983 (Box 38, Reel 1)
    5" reel-to-reel audiotape. Run time is 00:05:57.
  - Behind the Scenes: Thanksgiving #13, November 24, 1983? (Box 38, Reel 2)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at 00:05:07.
  - Behind the Scenes #14, December 2, 1983 (Box 38, Reel 3)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at 00:05:10.
  - Behind the Scenes: As you like it, A Christmas carol, Winche, romantic comedy, #15, December 8, 1983 (Box 38, Reel 4)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at 00:05:27.
  - Behind the Scenes #17, December 22, 1983 (Box 38, Reel 5)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at 00:04:58.
  - Behind the Scenes #18, December 29, 1983 (Box 38, Reel 6)
    5" reel-to-reel audiotape. Run time is 00:06:20.
  - Behind the Scenes: wrap up of '83, 1983 (Box 38, Reel 7)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Runt time is 00:05:26.
  - Behind The Scenes Claire Kincannon #20, January 13, 1984? (Box 38, Reel 8)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at 00:07:15.
  - Behind the scenes: Odd Couple, Busboy, Old Men, January 29, February 5, February 27, 1984? (Box 36)
    Videotape cassette.
  - Behind the Scenes, cut 1-5, April 4-11, 1984 (Box 36)
    Videotape cassette. Women in film: Streetwise, Old Enough; Gin Game; short run; Mayor of ?; End of World.
  - Behind the Scenes #32, April 6, 1984 (Box 39, Reel 9)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at 00:04:50.
  - Behind the Scenes Live WFFU Claire Kincannon/Barry Lee, May 17, 1984 (Box 38, Reel 10)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Run time is 00:26:46.
  - Behind the Scenes: Henry V, May 24, 1984 (Box 38, Reel 11)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at 00:04:06.
  - Behind the Scenes: Fools fire, J's Girls, July 6, 1984 (Box 38, Reel 12)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at 00:06:52.
  - Behind The Scenes: Olympics, August 1984 (Box 38, Reel 13)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at 00:05:16.
  - Behind the Scenes: Glass Menagerie, Calendar, August 24, 1984 (Box 38, Reel 14)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at 00:05:47.
  - Behind the Scenes: Sound of Music, Capital steps, August 31, 1984 (Box 40, Reel 1)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at 00:06:07.
  - Behind the Scenes with Claire Kincannon, September 1984 (Box 40, Reel 2)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at 00:03:44.
  - Behind the Scenes, 1 year old, September 6, 1984 (Box 40, Reel 3)
    5" reel-to-reel audiotape. Tape entered silence at approximately 00:05:30.
  - Behind the Scenes with Claire Kincannon: review of the Tempest (Arena), America Hurrah, Woolly Mammoth, October 20, 1984 (Box 40, Reel 5)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at approx 00:05:06.
  - Behind the Scenes With Claire Kincannon: Wrap up 84, January 3, 1985 (Box 40, Reel 5)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Box reads "Rebecca Rice Liv Stage", "#7, 10/12/83". Program ends at 00:07:11.
  - Musical! Show #852-3, master applause, hour 1, April 20, 1985 (Box 40, Reel 6)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program switches from stereo to mono (left channel only) from 00:02:50 until 00:04:22 Program ends at 00:26:23.
  - Behind the Scenes, cut 4, July 19, 1985 (Box 40, Reel 7)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Run time is 00:20:27. Approx 1 minute of silence before program begins.
  - Bits and pieces of broadway. Written and directed by Claire Kincannon, Musical show #853-4, hour 3, July 27, 1985 (Box 40, Reel 8)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Program ends at 00:21:50.
  - Cut 10, Htbrk hse, January 3, 1986 (Box 40, Reel 9)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Run time is 00:47:10.
  - Behind the scenes, cut 11: the Birthday Party, April 4, 1986 (Box 40, Reel 10)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Run time is 00:41:45.
  - Shakespeare Theatre Part 2, January 14, 1991 (Box 40, Reel 11)
    7" reel to reel audiotape. Program ends at approx 00:05:34.
  - Shakespeare at the Lansburg?; Press conference part 1, January 14, 1992 (Box 40, Reel 12)
    7" reel-to-reel audiotape. Run Time: 01:05:27.
  - Hungary remembered, produced by Claire Kincannon, undated (Box 35)
  - 35th anniversary Hungarian revolution, Ball, April, 1986 (Box 35)
  - Hungary, undated (Box 35)
  - Paul's painting and Ilona stills or Hungary 5, undated (Box 35)
  - Newsreels, Hungary tape 1, undated (Box 35)
  - Hungary tape 2, undated (Box 35)
  - spine reads: "Hungary 2", "Takacs and Pting", "only tape of P.T. on cam", undated (Box 35)
  - spine reads: "Hungary 1", "Ilona and pics of HME + Paul (pt one)", undated (Box 35)
  - spine reads "Hungary 3", front reads "#1 Shander 2/3"; "Blank 1/3"; "tape #1 Simmons", March 25, 1983 (Box 35)
  - "Hungary 4" or "Sandor 2", undated (Box 35)
  - Hungary 10, ball, sound only, undated (Box 35)
  - Hungary 11, sound only, take 3, undated (Box 35)
  - Hungary 9, Geveben and people, ball guests, take 1, undated (Box 35)
  - Black audio, undated (Box 35)
  - Black master, Hungary, undated (Box 35)
  - Film clips, undated (Box 36)
    Videotape cassette. Clips from Streetwise and Old Enough.